edsurge.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy | EdSurge

#### Last modified May 16, 2018

 **ATTENTION: PLEASE READ CAREFULLY THIS EDSURGE, INC. (“EDSURGE” OR “WE”) PRIVACY POLICY (“PRIVACY POLICY”), WHICH IS PART OF THE EDSURGE TERMS OF USE (COLLECTIVELY “TOU”), BEFORE YOU (“YOU”) ACCESS, DOWNLOAD, OR OTHERWISE USE THE WEBSITE.**

 **ACCESSING, DOWNLOADING OR OTHERWISE USING THE WEBSITE INDICATES THAT YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY IN FULL. IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT ACCESS, DOWNLOAD OR OTHERWISE USE THE WEBSITE.** You acknowledge (a) that You have read and understood this Privacy Policy; and (b) this Privacy Policy shall have the same force and effect as a signed agreement.

### 1\. Introduction

This Privacy Policy only applies to Your visits to <https://www.edsurge.com/> and applications on the Website, which is operated by EdSurge, Inc., a California corporation, with a principal place of business at 1801 Murchison Dr, Ste 220, Burlingame, CA 94010. We know You value Your privacy. This Privacy Policy governs information we receive from You or about You and explains how we may collect, use, and, in some instances, share this information. Other websites which are linked to/from <https://www.edsurge.com/> may have different policies; please review the privacy policies on those websites for details. 

Unless explicitly stated otherwise, any new features that augment or enhance the current Website will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is part of the EdSurge’s [TOU](https://www.edsurge.com/terms) . Any terms defined in the TOU shall have the same meaning in this Privacy Policy. 

Please review the Privacy Policy each time You use the Website. If we materially change this Privacy Policy, we will update this page to reflect any changes to this Privacy Policy and notify You by email, if we have Your email address. BY USING THE WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE MOST RECENT VERSION OF THE PRIVACY POLICY.

### 2\. Information We Collect

We collect information from You when You use the Website, contact, us or interact with us in the manner described below. We may collect personal information that You may provide. If You submit any personal information in connection with using the Website, You represent that You have the authority to do so and to permit EdSurge to use the information in accordance with the Privacy Policy.

#### A. Information You Voluntarily Provide Us

When You sign up to receive one of our newsletters, We collect your name and email address. When you submit information to us through our contact page or post comments to the Website, We collect your name, email address, and any other information that You provide to us. When You use the Website to post a job on the Edtech Job Board, use the Matching Service to create a profile to apply for posted jobs, or sign up for EdSurge newsletters, You may provide the following information to EdSurge:

  *  _Companies Posting Jobs on the Edtech Job Board:_

(1) _Company Registration:_ If You are a representative of a company or a third party that has contracted with a company that would like to post a job on the Edtech Job Board on behalf of the company, You will first need to register with the Website. When registering You will provide us with the following information: first and last name, email address, and a password used to log into the Website. We also ask for the following information: the name of Your company; company type; and a link to the company’s website (You must enter a URL). You will also provide Your information as a representative, including whether You are employed by the company, Your current position at the company, Your work email, and Your work phone number.

(2) _Posting a Job to the Edtech Job Board:_ After completing the company registration, a company will be able to post a job on the Edtech Job Board. As the company representative, You will provide us information related to the position, including job title, function of the job, and experience level desired, among other information.

On completion of the proposed job profile, You will be directed to a payment page prior to posting the job. All payment collection is handled by a third party provider, Stripe. Please review Stripe’s Privacy Policy (<https://stripe.com/us/privacy>) and Services Agreement (<https://stripe.com/us/legal>) for more information. 

  * _Users Creating a Profile for Utilizing Matching Services:_

(1) An individual user may also create a profile on the Website to utilize the Job Matching Service. As part of creating Your profile, You provide us information including first and last name, email address, current location in the United States, regions where you are currently looking for a job, the types of jobs You are looking for, amount of experience You have in the desired position, whether You are interested in a secondary role and level of experience in a secondary role, the experience level You are seeking in the next job, whether You are interested in a full time job, part time job, or an internship, whether You have previously worked in education/Edtech, any information You provide in an executive summary, which is a quick headline about You, a URL to Your LinkedIn profile, Your resume if You choose to upload one, and a list of companies that You do not want us to contact.

  *  _Users Subscribing to EdSurge Newsletters:_

(1) To subscribe to a newsletter, You will be required to fill out a short profile. You provide EdSurge information including whether You are interested in K12 or Higher Education, first and last name, email address, if You are interested in K12, Your role, and if You are interested in Higher Education, the organization type, and the organization name.

#### B. Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Website

When You access and use the Website, we automatically collect information regarding You and Your device, including Your device’s internet protocol address, the domain name of Your internet service provider, Your location, Your mobile device information (e.g., device model and operating system version), Your page visits, Your social sharing activity, and aggregated information that cannot be used to specifically identify You. Additional information collected is described in the **Analytics** and **Cookies, Local Storage and Other Tracking Technologies** sections below.

#### C. Information We Collect from Other Sources

We may collect information about You from third party sources including social media companies.

  *  **Twitter**. By clicking on the Twitter button on the Website, You will automatically be transported to the official Twitter feed of EdSurge, @EdSurge, <https://twitter.com/edsurge>. 
  * **Facebook**. By clicking on the Facebook button on the Website, You will be automatically transported to the official Facebook Page for EdSurge, <https://www.facebook.com/EdSurge/>. EdSurge allows users to comment on blog posts using the Facebook Comments Plugin and in doing so, EdSurge may have access to personal information about You. For more information on the Facebook Comments Plugin, please visit, <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/comments>. 
  * **LinkedIn**. By clicking on the LinkedIn button on the Website, You will be automatically transported to the official LinkedIn profile for EdSurge, <https://www.linkedin.com/company/edsurge/>. 
  * **YouTube**. YouTube is a Google/Alphabet service. By clicking on the YouTube button on the Website, You will be automatically transported to the official YouTube channel for EdSurge, <https://www.youtube.com/user/EdSurge>. 
  * **SoundCloud**. By clicking on the SoundCloud button on the Website, You will be automatically transported to EdSurge’s SoundCloud page, <https://soundcloud.com/edsurge>. 
  * **Eventbrite**. EdSurge uses Eventbrite to advertise and organize events in different cities in the United States. When You provide information to Eventbrite to register for EdSurge events, Eventbrite will share information You provided with us in accordance with its Privacy Policy, <https://www.eventbrite.com/support/articles/en_US/Troubleshooting/eventbrite-privacy-policy?lg=en_US>. If You register for a paid event, Eventbrite will not share Your financial information (like credit card number and expiration date, billing address, etc.) with us. 
  * **MeetUp**. EdSurge also uses MeetUp to organize events in different cities in the United States. When You provide information to MeetUp in creating a profile and/or registering for events, MeetUp may share some information with us pursuant to its privacy policy, <https://www.meetup.com/privacy/>. 
  * **MailChimp**. EdSurge uses MailChimp to create email subsets using subscriber email addresses. MailChimp may collect information from users subscribing to EdSurge newsletters, including name, physical address, email address, IP address, phone number, details including gender, occupation, and other demographic information. For more information, please visit MailChimp’s privacy policy: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>. 
  * **Marketo**. EdSurge uses Marketo to disseminate newsletters and/or to create email subsets using subscriber email addresses. According to Marketo’s Use Policy, it will not collect and we will not provide sensitive personal information, <http://legal.marketo.com/use-policy/>. 
  * **Google Play**. By clicking on the Google Play button on the Website, You will automatically be transported to the official Google Play page of EdSurge, <https://play.google.com/music/listen?u=0#/ps/I7nkf7dakczcktkcfo7enioewc4>. 
  * **Spotify**. By clicking on the Spotify button on the Website, You will automatically be transported to the official Spotify page of EdSurge, <https://open.spotify.com/show/5Omg7s9kRYFgt4jEynpdoL?si=rfUzBmV6QS6VsHTUqYKdHA>. 

EdSurge may also collect information about You as permitted or required by law. We may combine all of the information we collect from You and use it in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

### 3\. How We Use Your Information

We use the information that we collect for several purposes including:

  * The purposes for which You provided it;
  * To process and respond to Your inquiries;
  * For fulfillment of orders and requests;
  * To identify You as a user of the Site;
  * To connect with Your social media accounts;
  * To send You information about Your relationship with us;
  * To enable You to provide comments and participate in questions and answers;
  * To contact You with information, including promotional information, that we believe will be of interest to You;
  * To provide relevant advertising;
  * To share information about attendees with sponsors of an event, and to provide a list of job fair participants and their resumes to companies attending any job fair related events;
  * To provide the services You request, including the Site and the products and services made available through the Site;
  * To display relevant advertising and remarketing across websites;
  * To create anonymous data and to compile aggregate data, which we may use for any purpose, including for internal and external business purposes;
  * To analyze the Site;
  * To allow us to personalize and enhance Your experience using the Site;
  * To generate and review reports and data about our user base and service usage patterns;
  * To analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, usability or popularity of the Site;
  * To improve the Site or develop new products and services;
  * To compile aggregate data for internal and external business purposes;
  * To prevent fraudulent transactions and prevent misuse of services or offers, monitor against theft and otherwise protect our users and our business;
  * To administer and troubleshoot the Site; and
  * As otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy or the Terms or as permitted or required by law.

Please note that You may choose not to allow us to use Your personal information for certain purposes (such as to email You promotional information) as described in the **Your Choices Regarding Your Information** section below.

### 4\. How Your Information Is Disclosed

Information may be disclosed to third parties in accordance with our Privacy Policy. You may choose not to share certain information as described in the **Your Choices Regarding Your Information** below.

#### A. Third Party Service Providers and Business Partners

We may use third party service providers and business partners to perform functions in connection with the Website, such as site analytics, email marketing, social sharing, blog commenting, website administration, software maintenance, servicing, and upgrading, hosting, data migration, advertising, storing data, and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. We may share Your personal information with these service providers and business partners. We also may share users’ personal information with advertisers for their direct marketing and promotional purposes and so they can provide services to You.

#### B. Business Changes

If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may transfer Your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith.

#### C. Affiliates

We may also share Your information with our affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. Our affiliates will be required to maintain that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### D. Investigations and Law

We may disclose information about You to third parties if we believe that such disclosure is necessary to:

  * Investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, suspected fraud, the rights, reputation, safety, and property of us, users or others, or violations of our policies or other agreements with us;
  * Comply with the law or guidance and cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties;
  * Respond to claims and legal process (for example subpoenas); and/or
  * Protect against legal liability.

#### E. Aggregated Information

We may share aggregated information relating to users of the Website with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties. This aggregated information does not contain personal information about any user.

#### F. Analytics

We use third party analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Website. These tools may use cookies and other technologies to collect information about Your use of the Website. These tools collect information sent by Your device or the Website and other information that assists us in improving the Website. This information may be used to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, and better understand Your online activity.

We Use:

  *  **Google Universal Analytics**. We use Google’s Universal Analytics to better understand who is using the Website and how people are using it. Google Universal Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”) that uses cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to collect and store information such as Website pages visited, places where users click, time spent on each page, IP address, type of operating system used, location-based data, device ID, search history, and phone number. We use this information to improve the Website and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Please see <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/> for information about how Google Analytics uses this information, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> for information about the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, and visit <http://www.google.com/settings/ads/> to adjust the settings for Your Google account. Google Analytics may track You over time and across websites or applications. 
  * **ScoreCardResearch Beacon**. ScoreCardResearch Beacon is a service of Full Circle Studios, Inc. that assists in the collection of Internet web browsing information. ScoreCardResearch uses tagging and cookies to collect traffic data. For more information, and if You would like to opt-out of ScoreCardResearch, please visit its privacy policy, [https://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx?&newlanguage=1](https://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx?&newlanguage=1). By using the Website, You agree to allow ScoreCardResearch Beacon to collect diagnostic data to allow EdSurge to better operate the Website. 
  * **Bugsnag**. Bugsnag is a service used for monitoring and addressing website crashes and errors. Bugsnag imbeds a cookie on Your computer or mobile device to better analyze information. Bugsnag may collect error data which includes diagnostic data. According to Bugsnag, diagnostic data may consist of personal information including name, email address, username, IP address, and mobile device ID. For more information, please visit Bugsnag’s privacy policy, [ https://docs.bugsnag.com/legal/privacy-policy/](https://docs.bugsnag.com/legal/privacy-policy/). By using the Website, You agree to allow us to share diagnostic data with Bugsnag to 
  * **Chartbeat**. Chartbeat is a service of Chartbeat, Inc. that collects traffic data on EdSurge’s Website. Chartbeat may collect Your IP address to show geolocation information and browser type. For more information, please visit Chartbeat’s privacy policy, <https://chartbeat.com/privacy/>. By using the Website, You agree to allow us to share diagnostic data with Chartbeat to better address Website crashes and errors. 

### 5\. Cookies, Local Storage, and Other Tracking Technologies

These and other third parties may collect or receive information about Your use of the Website, including through the use of cookies, web beacons and other technologies, and this information may be collected over time and combined with information collected on different websites and online services, which may track users across websites and apps. You can instruct Your browser to stop accepting cookies. But if You do not accept cookies, You may not be able to use all functionality of the Website.

#### A. Cookies

When You visit the Website or advertisements appearing on the Website, EdSurge or third parties may use “cookies” which store certain information on Your device and which allow us to customize Your experience to better match Your interests and preferences, or to simply facilitate Your signing in to use the Website. Most browsers will allow You to erase cookies from Your device, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. However, if You block or erase cookies, we may not be able to restore any preferences or customization settings You previously specified, and our ability to personalize Your online experience would be limited. Please refer to Your browser instructions or “help” screen to learn more about these functions.

#### B. Web Beacons

Also, EdSurge or third parties may collect information from visits to the Website through the use of “Web Beacons.” Web Beacons are small graphic images or other programming code (also known as “web bugs,” “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) used to keep track of Your navigation through the Website and Your electronic communication with us. We may include Web Beacons in our web pages and email messages. Web Beacons may be invisible to You, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or email can act as a Web Beacon. Web Beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Website, to monitor how users navigate the Website, to count how many emails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed. Web Beacons may be used to collect personal information (for example, the email address associated with an email message). This information is sometimes known as “clickstream data.” We may use this data to analyze trends and statistics to improve Your online experience, or customer service.

We use cookies and other tracking technologies on the Website to help us understand and save Your preferences and interests so we can personalize Your future visits and compile data about website traffic and website interaction so that we can offer better website experiences and tools in the future.

With your permission, We may also use pixels. A pixel is a small piece of code that can be installed on a website so social sites can track effectiveness of advertisements created on social media.

  *  **Twitter Pixel**. We use Twitter Pixel tags to better understand how effective Our marketing is on the Website. The Twitter Pixel is governed by Twitter’s Privacy Policy, <https://twitter.com/en/privacy> and Terms of Service, <https://twitter.com/en/tos>. For more information on Your privacy options, please visit <https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies>. 
  * **Facebook Pixel**. We use Facebook Pixel to better understand how successful an advertisement is on Facebook by seeking what happened as a direct result of interacting with the posting. According to Facebook’s policies, You have the right to opt-out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting by visiting, <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>. For more information, please visit Facebook’s Data Policy at <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. 

### 6\. Security

We implement a variety of security measures to protect the safety of Your personal information when You enter, submit, or access Your personal information.

While we take reasonable measures to protect the information You submit via the Website against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. No Internet, email, or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free. Email or other messages sent through the Website may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information through the Website and take special care in deciding with which information You provide us. If You have any questions about security on our Website, please email us at feedback@edsurge.com.

We cannot guarantee that transmissions of Your personal information will be fully secure and that third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures or the security measures of our partners. WE ASSUME NO LIABILITY FOR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION DUE TO TRANSMISSION ERRORS, THIRD-PARTY ACCESS OR CAUSES BEYOND OUR CONTROL.

Any information collected through the Website is stored and processed in the United States. If You use our Website outside of the United States, You consent to have Your data transferred to the United States.

### 7\. Data Retention Policy

We will retain Your information for as long as You use the Website and for a reasonable time thereafter. Please note that some or all of the information we have collected may be required in order for the Website to function properly.

### 8\. Your Choices Regarding Your Information

You have choices regarding how EdSurge uses Your information:

#### A. Changing Your Information

You may ask to review, update, or have deleted any personal information collected by EdSurge on the Website. To do so, please send us an email asking to review or update Your personal information, or to have us delete Your personal information at [feedback@edsurge.com](mailto:feedback@edsurge.com). Also, if You created a profile for a company or for the Job Matching Service, You may log in to Your profile to change Your information. However, we reserve the right to retain personal information as necessary to comply with federal and state laws. 

#### B. Email Communications

You can make changes regarding receiving email communication from us by contacting us at [feedback@edsurge.com](mailto:feedback@edsurge.com). 

#### C. Social Media

You should make sure You are comfortable with the information that a third party social networking service may make available to us by carefully reviewing the social media service’s privacy policy and terms and conditions and by modifying Your privacy settings directly on that service.

#### D. Opt-Outs Available from Our Partners

To opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, You can visit the [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads?sig=ACi0TChClWuDJQVKWmsevbiuDlPT94cnkW9-ZxHX-ykjfeIQzLyiT7t2pPuk_4HqrTguLyhDtCwWn8O_KTQE-3a9WIVdUmcV63uRIcg-k8uMhJw4SlOVToMDMnIVQkCXEbzKl3WvhK-rkbaxzRiXH8gmBhHz6IOqUkMrRDXiTtlu89KrP5ee_Tg&hl=en) page. Please note that to the extent advertising technology is integrated into the Website, You may still receive advertisements even if You opt-out of tailored advertising. In that case, the ads will just not be tailored to Your interests. Also, we do not control any of the above opt-out links and are not responsible for any choices You make using these mechanisms or the continued availability or accuracy of these mechanisms. 

See **Analytics** and **Cookies, Local Storage and Other Tracking Technologies** sections above for other partner opt-out details.

### 9\. Information Collected from Other Websites, and EdSurge’s Do Not Track Policy

Through cookies we place on Your browser or device, we and our partners may collect information about Your online activity after You leave the Website. Just like any other usage information we collect, this information allows us to improve the Website and customize Your online experience, and otherwise as described in this Privacy Policy.

Your browser may offer a “Do Not Track” option, which allows You to signal to operators of websites and mobile applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that You do not wish such operators to track certain of Your online activities over time and/or across different websites and mobile applications and services. The Website does not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that we collect information about Your online activity both while You are using the Website and after You leave the Website.

### 10\. Children

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from an individual under age 13. If You are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the Website. If You have reason to believe that we may have accidentally received personal information from an individual under age 13, please contact us immediately at [feedback@edsurge.com](mailto:feedback@edsurge.com). 

### 11\. Terms of Use

Please also visit EdSurge’s TOU at <https://www.edsurge.com/terms>, which state the terms, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing Your use of the Website. 

### 12\. Changes to the Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, and especially before You provide any information. Your continued use of the Site or provision of personal information after any modifications to this Privacy Policy constitutes Your acceptance of those changes. This Privacy Policy was made effective on the date indicated above.

### 13\. Your California Privacy Rights

Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code permits California residents to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information about the types of personal information the business has shared with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. You may make one request each year by emailing us at [feedback@edsurge.com](mailto:feedback@edsurge.com). 

### 14\. How to Contact Us

If You have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our use of Your personal information, please contact us at [feedback@edsurge.com](mailto:feedback@edsurge.com) or 

1801 Murchison Dr. #220  
Burlingame, CA 94010  
Attention: Privacy Officer

Telephone: (650) 485-3740
